good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICI Lombard General
Insurance company limiteds Q2 and H1 fy4
earnings conference call from the Senior
Management we have with us today Mr
barav Das Gupta MD and CEO of the
company Mr gopal balachandran CFO and
cro Mr sanjie mantri executive director
and Mr Alo karwal executive
director please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all all
participant lines will be in the listen
only mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star 10 on a
touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr bav Das Gupta MD and CEO ICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
pleas you sir thank you ziko and good
evening to each one of you thank you for
joining the earnings conference call of
I Lombard General insance limited
company for Q2 and H1
fi4 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months post this our CFO Mr gopal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the half year ended
September 30
2023 the global economy is experiencing
experiencing a lot of moment momentum
however the Indian economy is gaining
strength led by domestic drivers such as
private consumption and fixed asset
Investments by public sector
capex the Southwest Monsoon rainfall
recovered during September however it
ended below the long period average the
manufacturing and services pmis and
other high frequency indicators ex
exhibited a robust expansion during this
quarter on the demand front Urban
consumption is buyant while rural demand
is showing some signs of Revival however
the current geopolitical conditions and
higher interest rates in the advanced
economies can impact Global and domestic
economic growth negatively and we have
to Be watchful of the same for the
quarter as per data published by CM the
new Private Car Sales continue to
deliver robust growth year on year the
two wheer sales registered moderate
growth for the quarter and in terms of
volume Still Remains below the pre
pandemic levels the commercial vehicle
growth was driven by growth in infra and
other cor sectors health insurance
continue to deliver rer growth growth
remaining the large contributed to
overall growth the commercial segment
witnessed growth in line with the
current market environment we remain
optimistic that the industry will
continue to grow given the favorable
macros regulatory changes low
penetration and relatively positive
consumer
sentiment speaking of the performance
The General insurance industry delivered
a gdpi growth of 14.9% for the first
half of this year over the first half of
last year excluding the crop insurance
growth is at 18% for the same period
overall the underwriting performance
versent with a combined ratio of the
industry at 13.3% for q1 fi 24 as
against 11.4 for q1
fi23 for motor business while the
combined ratio continues to remain
elevated the combine ratio for the
industry improved to
12.1% from q1 2024 as against 124.5 for
q1
2023 moving to the business numbers for
us in Q2 fi 2024
the company grew at
17.4% as compared to the industry growth
of 12
12.5% in terms of growth for key
segments during the quarter Property and
Casualty line of business grew at 17.2%
which was higher than the industry
growth of
8.6% further during the quarter we acced
market share across all segments such as
fire Marine engineering and
liability in motor our growth for the
quarter was 10.9% as against the
industry growth of 13.9 % the growth in
motor segment was aided by robust growth
of 37.6% in the new Private Car segment
the private car mix stands at 51.8% for
the for this quarter while the
competitive intensity in the motor
segment remained elevated we continue
our focus of developing a quality
portfolio based on granular data we
continue to rebalance our portfolio
resulting in commercial vehicle mix at
22.1% and two wheer mix at 26.1% for
Quarter Two of this
year we we also continue to harness our
digital capabilities in building claims
efficiency in motor in Q2 fi 24 through
our preferred partner Network PPN
Network we were able to service 63% of
our non OEM claims up from 44% in Q2 of
2023 the health segment continues to be
the fastest growing segment for the
industry during this quarter we grew at
20.3% as a result of our continued
investment in retail Health distribution
we have grown in line with the industry
at
18.7% this was driven by growth in
business s to the retail health agency
vertical of
21.7% I would also like to share that
our OneStop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs I take care app has
surp surpass 6.9 million uh user
download till date the incremental
download for the quarter was 1.3 million
for Q2 of fi 24 the premium Source
through I take care app contributed to
88457 million to the overall gdpi
reflecting a 3 .5 times increase year on
year we have been updating you about our
digital business initiatives like
digital wand and I take care which we've
been driving in an agile manner we are
now scaling these agile models to
business lines across the company
completely re redefining the ways of
working and the business processes
coupled with the transformation of the
core system we expect this to be a key
driver for our future growth as a
digitally impart insurance
company As You Are all uh you may be
aware I have decided to pursue an
overseas opportunity after spending over
14.5 years with ICA Lombard it has been
a wonderful Journey for me and I'm
grateful for the collective support of
all our stakeholders our employees
customers Channel Partners analysts and
shareholders we have made large strides
in the industry and made I a much loved
brand brand as India's largest private
sector GI player I take this opportunity
to thank all of you for your support and
hope you will extend the same support as
I pass on the beton to my dear colleague
sanjie
mantri sanjie has been with the icsi
group gr for over 20 years sanjie has
played a St Stellar role in terms of his
achievement within the company he
spearheaded the retail division as an
executive director where he was leading
distribution of products across agency
Bank Insurance direct and Alternate
channels he was also in charge of the
strategy products pricing marketing and
corporate communication vertical at IC
Lombard I'm convinced that IC Lombard
will continue to be a strong force of
positive change in the industry under
his leadership over to you sanj thank
you bar leadership is an inspiration for
all of us and your St record over the
last 15 years has left an indel impact
on the organization and the industry at
large we are excited for you and the
opportunities that lie ahead and wish
you the very best I'm keenly looking
forward to taking the journey ahead and
we rely heavily on the support of all
our stakeholders these are interesting
times for the GI industry and we are
very well positioned to capitalize on
this I look forward to meeting and
interacting with each one of you
personally we will continue to remain
focused on our overall philosophy of
balancing growth and
profitability I will now request gopal
to take you through the financial
numbers for the Recently concluded
quarter and half year thanks
than good evening to each I now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year we have uploaded
the result presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers the gross direct
premium income of the the company was at
R 24.72 billion in H1 f524 as against
rupes 10 15.55 billion in H1 fi23 a
growth of 18.2% as against industry
growth of
14.9% excluding crop GDP of the company
was at
17.6% which was in line with industry
growth of 18% in quarter to
f524 gdpi was at R 6.86 billion in Q2 as
against 51.85 billion rupees in Q2 fi23
a growth of 17 .4% this growth was
higher than the industry growth of
12.5% our gdpi growth during the quarter
was primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segment the overall gdpi of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 17.2% at 14.76 billion rupees in
quarter 2 fi 24 as against R 12.59
billion in quarter to
fi23 on the retail side of the business
GDP of the motor segment was at R 2.38
billion in quarter to fi 24 as against r
19.28% due to fi23 registering a growth
of
10.9% the advanced premium numbers was
at rupes
32.892880
billion in Q2 fi23 registering a growth
of
20.3% our agents which included the
point of sale distribution count was was
at 122
461 as on September 30 2023 up from
around
17,49 as on june3 2023 GDP of the retail
Health segment grew by
19% Group Health segment that's the
corporate employer employee segment grew
by 20.6% during the quarter the bank
insurance and kg group grew at 24.3%
this quarter during the quarter of
business source through our digital one
team grew by
26.7% overall our digital Focus has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues which includes the IL take care
app Business to rupees 3.66 billion
which accounts for 6% of our overall
gdpi for the
quarter Rec resultantly the combined
ratio was 103.7 for H1 FY 24 as against
10 14.6% for H1
fi23 excluding the impact of cat losses
of r83 billion in H1 f24 and r28 billion
in H1 fi23 the combined ratio was 10
12.7% and 10 14.2% respectively combined
ratio was 103.9 in quarter 2 fi 24 as
against 10 5.1% in quarter to fi23
excluding the impact of C lesses of
rupes 48 billion in Q2 fi 24 and r28
billion in Q2 fi23 the combined ratio
was 10 2.8% and 10 14.3% respectively
our investment assets Rose to rupees
45312 billion as at September 30 2023 up
from rupes 44905 billion as at June 30
2023 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.07 times as at
September 30 2023 as against 4.16 times
as at June 30 2023 investment income was
at r
17.59% at R 9.36 billion in Q2 fi 24 as
against rupes 7.39 billion in Q2 fi23
our capital gain net of empowerment or
investment assets stood at rupes 2.87
billion in H1 fi 24 as compared to rupes
1.43 billion in H1
fi23 capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at R 1.65
billion in Q2 fi4 as compared to rupes
1.11 billion in Q2 fi23 our profit
before tax grew by 19.4% at R 12.84
billion in H1 f24 as against R 10.75
billion in H1 fi23 whereas CBT grew by
25.3% at 7.64 billion in Q2 f524 as
against rupes 6.10 billion in Q2 fi23
consequently profit after tax grew by 3%
at R 9.68 billion H1 f24 as against R
9.40 billion in Hy H1 fi23 P degw by
2.2% Ates 5.77 billion in Q2 f24 from
rupees 5.91 billion in Q2
fi23 operator request has been initiated
if you'd like to cancel this request
please press do Z again 2% in H1
f24
and 24.8% in Q2
f524 return on average Equity was 18% in
H1 fi
fi23 the Roe for quarter 2 fi 24 was
21.1% as against 24.5% in quarter 2 fi23
solcy ratio was at 2.59 times as at
September 1th 2023 as against 2.53 times
as at June 30 2023 continued to be
higher than the regulatory minimum
requirement of 1.5 times the board of
directors of theany company has declared
interim dividend of rupes 5 per share
for H1 fi2 24 as against rupes 4.5 per
share for H1
fi23 as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safeguarding the
interest of policy holders at all times
I would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any specific
questions that you have thank you thank
you very much we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on their Touchstone telephone if
you wish to withdraw yourself from the
question Q you may press star and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question ladies
and gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question Q
assembles
our first question is from the line of
ainash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead yeah hi good evening uh thanks for
the opportunity uh uh best wishing to
you Vargo for your future endeavors and
congratulations to Sanju on his new role
uh uh good set of performance couple of
questions uh first one uh I mean on your
motor side of course uh you commented
about the competitive intensity
uh but whatever I see incrementally in
your quarter two overall motor
profitability seems to be quite good for
you yet you remain sort of very very
guarded with the motor I mean so why
such I would say the guarded approach
even when profitability seems to be
suggesting that okay uh things are
better than what they were a few
quarters back so that is on your entire
strategy around motor because even in
motor CV you have started to sort of a
uh take a bit of more business but again
there you it seems that okay you have
sort of trying to slow down so on on
overall motor I would like to understand
the philosophy and on the same point now
I guess if I understand the regulation
correctly now even motor TP technically
a commission is sort of a possible
because I mean the business line wise
commission caps are gone so what is sort
of a practices you are witnessing in the
market as far as motor is concerned so
that's on motor and on Health uh I of
course I see that okay uh the uh results
are coming from your focus on agency and
that sort of leading to sort of a growth
in retail yet if I see because you are
growing uh strongly in the group both on
the banker side as well as a employer
employee uh your mix is Shifting again
more towards uh group I mean of course
the Bankai is largely retail I
understand yet I'm saying that on your
individual side uh I mean is that growth
still a bit your Cali ated or why I mean
uh because on the group employers
employee side if I understand the price
hike is now behind so it would be
largely kind of a volum l growth so that
growth is a strong B growth is strong is
I mean so on the pure pure retail why
sort of a bit of slow as for your own
experience so the two question thank
you thanks and maybe sanj can answer the
question yeah sure so thanks a clearly
from a motor perspective as you ly said
there are enough and more Tails
available at the industry level and we
are well set to capitalize uh in a way
in your question itself I see the answer
that we are able to drive it profitably
because we have kept ourselves
calibrated and we have also always
maintained that we will move where we
see an opportunity in terms of profit
pool uh if you look at our own uh
configuration of motor portfolio overall
you will see that the CV portfolio has
marginally gone down in terms of a
contribution in H1 of 23.4 it moved to
21.6 and we have growth on private car
and two wheer as a company uh if you ask
me in terms of the view the way we
expect ourselves we we would continue to
exert what is required uh but if you see
intensity which is uh in our mind not
working out overall we will probably be
attack trous in terms of driving it so
overall our plan of uh being a
competitive and being in this play
because this is where a key distribution
is we will continue to exert ourselves
as a team uh on the health part which
you spoke about in terms of growth
coming famili from Group Health rather
than retail uh if you see our investment
largely has been on the retail side and
there you'll see a Delta over industry
growth of 2% uh Group Health we always
maintained that we going strategically
if we see that we are able to uh see
some sanity in terms of pring we going
deep that's what we did in quarter one
but in Quarter Two If you see we have
grown rather subdued Vis is the market
uh that plan per se for us as a company
uh will not change but our trajectory on
the retail side is far more permanent
and you will see us doing much better
there's a marginal Improvement in market
share but I would not like to read too
much into that because over a period of
time we would do uh much better and we
continue to stay invested as far as
health agency is
concerned yeah thank you and that
question regarding you know current
practices around Commissions in motor
because I mean technical now I mean one
can pay commissions on motor PP as well
so what sort of a market I mean post the
sort of you know basically the
commission caps are going to um cap what
kind of a market practices you are
seeing as far as the pay offs are
concerned so ainash clearly we spoke
about the industry level numbers on
motor and we see a marginal Improvement
in the overall combined ratio from 124
is moved to 120 uh Frankly Speaking
there is not too much you can read in
those numbers as far as this this point
of even on expense of management while
it does come in you see almost 50% of
the company being more than the limit
which is there which is stated uh have
we seen uh overall rationality
prevailing across uh Frankly Speaking
the industry itself is adjusting
adjusting to it at this point of time
and over a period of time I do believe
that you will see far more
rationalization than what's happened now
and we we do expect stability to come in
by quarter three or quarter four in
overall from an overall
perspective okay thank you thank
you thank you our next question is from
the line of sha Shivani from clsa please
go
ahead yes uh thank you for the
opportunity and congratulation on a good
set of numbers uh so sir on the coming
back on the motor book I wanted some
more understanding on uh the loss ratio
Improvement that has happened in 1 H
versus 1q uh I know you don't want us to
look us on look at loss ratios on
quarterly basis but if even even the 1ed
numbers look quite good so that would be
one question uh second is on the uh
monthly performance so uh while I
understand your monthly performances do
vary but if you can give us some color
in uh understanding what specifically
happened in probably August and
September because till July you guys
were had a very strong run rate of about
20% so uh any color now around what
happened and uh any growth Outlook that
you can uh give and so so one more
question third question probably uh
you've launched a new product with ICC
pro life the health and protection
product uh management mentioned in the
conference call yesterday so if you can
give us some understanding of the
economics of such a product you know uh
premiums uh the way uh partnership with
IC Pro works out I'm assuming this will
get sold on the IC back platform so some
color on
that yeah so so sh uh I think on the
first one I think if you look at uh on
the loss ratios for motor um I think
you're right I think we keep saying that
you should never look at numbers uh over
quarters or even let's say even on a
financial year basis because some of
these lines will obviously kind of start
to exhibit U outcomes over a relatively
longer period of time particularly in
the context of motor third party uh
having said that I think when you look
at even for let's say the half year uh
on motor OD specifically engine what we
have talked about is the portfolio loss
ratio should kind of range between the
65 to 70% kind of threshold on motor own
damage uh for the half year I think that
number is at let's say 65% or thereabout
but that's the range at which you would
possibly see depending on what kind of a
business mix that we write in terms of
whether we are able to relatively pick
up pick up a higher proportion of uh new
or let's say relatively what kind of
proportion are we able to write in the
context of the older portfolio so that's
broadly the range at which we will be
able to operate at within quarters
obviously the loss ratios will undergo a
change but that's the range that we are
comfortable with in so far as uh the own
damage book is concerned on third party
again the point is still the same I
think while for the quarter you would
have again seen the number slightly
better or let's say even on a half
yearly basis uh I think the number
stands at about 66% but these are
experiences that one should logically
again look at uh over relatively longer
periods uh and also to the fact that
depending on what kind of a mix of
business that we write in terms of
Private Car two- wheeler and CV and
that's something that we keep
calibrating from time to time
corresponding to which you could
possibly see a change in the loss ratio
uh experience uh but otherwise there's
nothing specific to call out in the
context of let's say uh the uh quarter
two numbers having said that I think
what we also keep doing is given the
fact that from a reserving perspective
generally we have tried to be prudent at
all points of time that philosophy still
continues to remain the same uh even as
we write whichever portfolio of the book
but over a period of time as you would
have seen some of our experiences have
actually started to turn out to be much
much positive and let's say what our
initial estimates have been so that will
obviously get calibrated from time to
time but otherwise in so far as overall
portfolio is concerned it's purely a
function of what kind of mixes mix of
business that that we able to write just
to add to a point that gopal made is
that the way we look at businesses on a
combined basis not just loss ratio uh
and overall you should study your
numbers on a combined perspective
because certain businesses may have
higher expenses uh you know lower loss
isue and vice versa so as a as a team we
look at overall combined as a as a
object for for the combo product that
got mentioned yes we really excited we
have uh taken the term and the uh CHR
product of our and given a com combined
offering to our customers through our
agency channel uh if you look at it uh
crew has a very decent agency practice
and we have very decent Bank structures
and there was a gap which needed to be
filled we have created this product line
to you know leverage on each other's
distribution and as for the regulatory
environment that is there it's something
which is a very feasible option we have
gone ahead and done this uh partnership
with them and we expect this product to
probably ramp up in time to come uh to
be very honest our agents will require a
bit of a training process it will come
with a lag over a period of time but but
that being said we really excited with
this partnership that we have done with
them to drive uh the combo product in
the market which in many ways is first
of its kind and last questions s on the
monthly performance numbers again I
think that's purely a function of uh
what kind of businesses do we write
between periods uh as we had explained
even in the earlier call our business do
tend to have a bit of cality across
businesses uh so for example in quarter
one you will obviously see a relatively
higher proportion of some of the
commercial lines being underwritten in
Quarter Two we do see businesses booked
particularly in the context of crop now
that could get booked in a in a
particular month and therefore to that
extent you may possibly see variations
in growth percentages uh when you look
at it relatively on a month-on-month
basis but here again as we keep saying I
think a better way to look at given the
cyclicality of the business that we get
get to see maybe for example quarter
three you will see a lot more business
largely driven through let's say some of
the retail growth uh so again you may
see let's say month- on-month changes
between segments of businesses uh but
however when you look at it on a full
year basis I think in line with what we
have spoken uh last day looking at
looking at the way how how things are
positively shaping up for us uh we
should definitely look at ending the
year within that High Teens percentage
growth that we have talked about and uh
in general I mean depending on what
Sanji also mentioned uh on the of
management side I think if things starts
to get uh improved much better from an
industry perspective then the relative
outperformance that we have talked about
of 100 200 basis point over and above
the market growth rate that's something
that we still believe we will be able to
achieve got it sir thank you this
answers my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of nides from invest Tech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
uh what is the share of OEM and non OEM
business in the motor and how it has
been trending over last two to three
years overall if you see in our split in
terms of the motor that they speaking
about we would almost have 70% getout of
a business coming from the OEM business
and the rest would be coming through
other channels which the agency and Bank
Insurance sure I think last year we
articulated Our intention to to move
towards uh to increase share of non OEM
uh by focusing on high loss ratio low
low expense ratio uh business uh so how
is the progress on that has a share of
non OEM going up so uh overall if you
see again uh uh incrementally yes we
intend exercising ourselves more on the
agency side but uh the manner in which a
motor book has got created uh there's a
fair amount of contribution and if we
see an opportunity there it's not one
for the other we'll continue to invest
extensively on the agency business side
but that being said o where we have been
working for years and built a franchise
we will continue to drive that uh so we
need to look at both of both of these in
a in a standalone there there are times
that OEM contribution can go really up I
mean I me there's a season coming in
quarter 3 obviously you'll find again
OEM you know uh probably showing a
larger percentage but that being said
agency business should continue to do
well uh but relatively to put percentage
pool would be a very uh difficult option
it's not one for the other so NES just
to add to supp what sanj said I think
strategically and philosophically while
we are investing there will be times
when OEM will again come back up right
so if new vehicle sales increase as has
happened as we said in the opening
remarks uh I think the share of new
vehicle sales has been very positive for
us and those are profitable pools so
when we see those opportunities we want
to guard
them sure understood understood secondly
I noticed that there is some change in
the Senior Management Personnel uh
structure uh so uh if you can explain
what is the rational for that and what
is this Emerging Market group uh if you
can share some details on that Emerging
Markets group so effectively it's a very
minor change not a significant change
but we have an experienced resource
which has joined in and he's an expert
in terms of driving the emerging market
so we have pulled him in to report into
uh Alo which otherwise had a multiple
reporting so we want to use the benefit
of his presence in the
system and Emerging Market group is a is
a commercial lines or Emerging
Market operates across channels and
business lines basically this is the you
know bat rather than the top cities
right so this is where if you remember
last year we had done a little bit of uh
you know structuring change where
agal was Ed looking after after
wholesale business was given specific
Focus or given charge of that that
market with specific focus and we are
investing and we are growing that
business uh so typically let's say the
top 40 cities would be not there but
thereafter it would be considered to be
a sure sure thank you that's it from my
side thank you thank
you ladies and gentlemen in order to
ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in the conference please limit your
questions to one or two per participant
should you have a follow-up question we
would request you to rejoin the queue
thank you our next question is from the
line of sanet G from Evis spark please
go ahead yeah uh thank you thank you for
the opportunity uh uh my first question
is that whether whether you want to
preone your guidance of
102.5 to be achieved because because X
of cat cat if I see you are almost there
uh uh what what we have thought we will
achieve it by exit of fi25 so so just
wanted to understand uh whether whether
uh given given the underwriting
environment you believe that could
happen little quicker than expected
that's Point number one and and second
within within the uh this 102.5 or
combined ratio Improvement uh mean the
some some vitage was expected to come
from the Opex part but despite um um our
Opex compared to last year still still
has been higher or or in one also it's
higher so just wanted to understand that
eom is overall dragging the opic low
higher or increasing the op on the
higher side or or you believe sanity
will come and um will expense ratios
will improve for the
sector sankit cut a bit of slack to the
team right I you know you just you're
delivering better than expected numbers
and that's what we want to continue to
do uh no change in guidance as you know
the market is still very competitive
talked about where the combined isue for
the industry is in terms of motor share
motor segment uh but clearly I think
over the last one year the team has done
a brilliant job in terms of uh uh you
know significantly calibrating uh the
business as also building a lot of
capability on the cost side both on the
claims and and expense side uh so I
think you know we the team is doing
really well but there's no need to
change guidance as we see it at this
point in time on the cost side I'll ask
gopal to answer yeah so I think sanket
we will we will still continue to
maintain what we have been kind of
talking about which is uh I think the
businesses has always have to be looked
at as what bar also just mentioned in
response to the earlier one which is we
always look at the businesses from an
overall combined perspective uh because
different businesses would obviously
have a mix of let's say loss experience
and let's say the expense ratios as well
uh just to kind of uh look at the
overall expense of management
specifically to answer your point uh
first half of last year our expense of
management was at
27.3 relative to that if you look at our
first half of this year we are at about
26.9 uh so hence to that extent even
from an eom perspective we have actually
seen a marginal Improvement in line with
what we definitely wanted to kind of
drive it towards and this is despite the
fact that we continue to make our
investments in those areas of building
Distribution on health agency technology
some of the core trans project that we
talked about I think clearly we would
want to continue to make those
Investments and hence to that extent you
may not suddenly see a big shift
happening in so far as specifically in
the context of the expense ratio numbers
are concerned we will obviously Drive uh
a a positive change but having said that
I think we will directionally be more
Guided by the other objective that we
have specifically spelled out which got
rated as we speak which is the combined
ratio objective of 102% is something
that we want to achieve by the end of
next year so that's something that we
want to clear drive and as I said purely
uh the breakdown of expense is function
of loss and expenses got it got it one
just just last two questions or one
question which is one data keeping
typical loss ratio of retail health and
Group Health uh that that is you can
share and second I just just wanted to
understand this IL take care app 6% of
gwp is is a big big achievement so so
how do you see this to be contributing
and and and if you can give a color how
much is mix driven by motor and help in
in I Tech
carea so so the number of 6% is the
digital contribution uh sanet the second
point the second part of your question
uh so therefore to that ex that also
includes let's say the business that we
Source through I take care act and as we
have been talking about I think
consistently whether you look at it on a
year- on-ear basis obviously there is a
multiplier increase in so far as the
premium that we are sourcing through I
take care is concerned roughly about 3.7
times increase that we have seen uh but
even when you look at it on a sequential
basis I think we have been able to kind
of grow the contributions coming in that
particular uh particular app so we are
very very excited with the way how
things are getting played out and U
equally we are getting to see a lot more
uh product per customer in so far as the
use of the app is concerned and that
will continue to drive both uh volumes
as well as let's say value of premium in
so far as the digital contribution is
concerned uh to your first point in so
far as the break break down of the loss
ratios are concerned I think for Quarter
Two uh the breakdown of the overall
health loss ratios into corporate health
and Retail Indemnity corporate Health
loss ratios are at about 102% and the
retail Health Indemnity loss ratios are
66.6% now this number I think when when
the numbers that we gave out for quarter
one last year corporate Health was about
92.6 and the retail Health inity numbers
for 64.2 now obviously these numbers
have to be looked at in the context of
how do we see some of the loss
insurances play out and particularly in
quarter 2 we do get to see a slight
increase in loss Insurance primarily
because typically it's a monsoon season
and we get to see a lot more increase in
uh health related ailments that we get
to see and this is not specifically only
for this particular quarter 2 even
otherwise when you look at it even for
the last year for example clearly we had
seen an increase in the loss ratios
playing out between let's say a quarter
two versus a quarter one so hence in
that sense I I think we are pretty much
okay with the way how the loss
experiences is playing out and as we had
indicated in so far as the portfolio
growth is concerned I think it is coming
at a price at which we are comfortable
with and uh in the subsequent quarters
we should start seeing some of these
loss ratios getting normalized
particularly in the context of lowering
down of loss insurances that we see in
Q3 and Q4 just to supplement what gopal
said you know and we've talked about
this in the past the entire thought
process uh and the and the approach
behind I Tech care was uh consumer
engagement right engaging with our
customers be it you know uh the employer
employee segment where the individual is
a potential retail customer or a retail
customer b2c customer who comes on board
and uh and the approach that we are
taking is that as we have more engaged
customers they will renew better we will
have cross sale opportunities and
hopefully the relationship will be more
sticky so principally for us whatever
business we get as as long as it's
viable we are not driving motor numbers
or health numbers there it's a customer
engagement app and uh and and as an
organization we don't want to split that
number at this point in time to say okay
this is my motor number this is my
health number because it might drive us
in a manner which is not customer
Centric uh so uh so as an organization
we've been giving the numbers in terms
of number of app downloads the total
volume of cross and upsale business that
we doing which is something that we'll
continue
to thank you sorry to interrupt Mr
sankit GA may we request that you return
to the question que for followup
questions as there are several
participants waiting for their turn
thank you
sir our next question is from the line
of swab mukarji from bnk secur please go
ahead hi sir thank you for the
opportunity and congrats on a good set
of numbers so I'll again come back to
you know the motor loss ratios so uh I
understand that what you have
articulated in terms of uh your
experience and maybe some releases that
are coming uh but just you know for a
view of how the loss ratios are going to
pan out I mean say for in motor TP uh
your loss ratios have been little bit
fluctuating over quarters uh right now
that there has been a bit of a
Improvement going ahead if you can give
some color for the full year how we
should think about this number where it
can sustain uh same for OD given that uh
you you are picking up on growth uh on
the only business and particularly
private vehicle in the mix how confident
would you be in kind of maintaining this
kind of loss ratio so that is the first
one and uh secondly uh in terms of the
investment income I just wanted to
understand the yield that you have shown
realized return
is clearly strong I think slightly
higher than what we have done in the
past so is there certain uh you know you
know tactical bets that have you know
that have worked out which might not
play out in the coming quarters so and
what kind of eal we can think about for
the you know going ahead on a normalized
basis yeah that's so SP up on the first
one I think uh which is what I kind of
responded uh to the earlier one uh and
one had kind of talked about the range
at which we would be comfortable so one
I think when we look at motor as a line
of business we obviously look at it
again more from a combined perspective
which will be a combination of both the
loss experience and let's say the
expense ratios and as what we just
discussed again it will depend on what
proportion of new business that we write
because new typically comes with a
relatively better loss experience and
correspondingly let's say the expense
ratios could slightly stay elevated and
correspondingly let's say the older
portfolios as we just discussed
typically comes with a slightly high LR
and let's say a relatively lower cost of
distribution so honestly that will be a
interplay that one one would get to see
in so far as writing this book is
concerned but having said that I think
the range at which one would be
comfortable to operate in the context of
motor own damage is what I had kind of
responded earlier which is in the range
of between 65 to 70% depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
the in in respect of proportion of uh uh
new or let's say the relatively older
portfolio on third party again pretty
much we have kind of talked about as
what I responded obviously you should
can not look at these numbers uh
particularly for quarters or let's say
even on a halfly basis uh you have to
look at the numbers over relatively
longer period uh so there again it will
be a function of what uh kind of uh loss
experiences that one sees but broadly I
would say that one could see the third
party loss ratios again kind of hovering
around what you see on a full year basis
uh that would be largely representative
of the range range at which we would get
to see the loss ratio play out so that's
the response uh to your first one uh to
your second one on the overall uh
investment book uh I think uh in fact in
the past quarters people have been
asking us why have we not seen let's say
so much of an increase in the overall uh
interest income of the portfolio uh now
if you recollect I think what we
generally do is uh depending on the
market opportunity that one sees is how
we place our overall portfolio at and
for example we tend to kind of in this
High interest rate en government we
obviously want to capitalize the
opportunity that one sees in so far as
uh approval to the book is concerned and
which is why our overall uh duration of
the book um in fact stands at about 5.23
years this number if I remember it
correctly uh at the end of the at the
beginning of the year uh was at about
4.99 years so obviously we have gone a
bit long and we have kind of rightly
positioned the portfolio in order to
capitalize as I said the increased uh uh
interest rates that one sees in the
market uh so hence to that extent we
will obviously get to see this kind of
play out even as we kind of head into
the subsequent quarters what is it that
you will not necessarily see playing out
over the subsequent period is purely a
function of the extent of capital gains
that one sees in the market that's
purely driven by let's say the market
opportunity that one sees and even in
the past we have talked about it uh
between quarters you can always see
fluctuations in the breakup of the
overall investment income uh depending
on how Market plays out is what you will
be able to see some kind of games
playing out so so hence answer your
point I think uh the way we are
positioned the portfolio is what is
helping us in terms of capitalizing the
uh increased uh uh interest
income and just to just to supplement
the point that gopal made uh this is
we've been talking about this that our
Carri yield will increase and Go's given
this number if you also look at the
split of the unrealized gains the
unrealized gains the equity book has
increased uh at the end of this quarter
uh obviously on the debt side and the
bond side has come down because interest
rates have gone gone up but that is not
something that we worried about because
these are all uh calls that we've taken
to stay long in uh in the debt Market
that's how our yield has
increased understood sir yeah but thank
you so much and all the best thank
thanks
much thank you our next question is from
the line of Rishi junjun Wala from iifl
institutional equities please go Ahad
yeah thanks for the opportunity just a
couple of questions uh uh firstly you
know this September month would have
seen the first 5year anniversary of the
two-wheeler long-term TP um so how has
the experience been in terms of renewal
it is you know given that 5 years of TP
means that the renewals have pretty much
down to zero and and as a result uh you
know if you can give some color in terms
of what would you know that amount of
premium for September month b as
proportion of overall motor
TP so uh thanks clearly yes this was the
first month uh overarchingly if you ask
me overall industry level there's a good
reason why I think Supreme Court get
thect in terms of having long-term
thisis uh the retention rates uh
continue to be relatively on the lower
side I would not split in terms of the
amount but retention levels that we are
seeing as a team right now around 15 to
20% uh development of this uh will
happen over you know summation of
probably a quarter in terms of what are
the two numbers because we'll have to
pursue this uh uh with our own customers
and see where we end up losing it uh but
it's but it's something as a pool that
we very keen so we're using all possible
analytics to see if we can further
sharpen our X and see that uh we can
dite these numbers uh even if it's only
TP we'll be more than happy to write
this pool
understood and the second is uh just on
the total payouts to the distribution uh
channels um you know some of our uh life
insurance peers have talked about uh you
know industrywide increase in payouts uh
to the distribution channels um how has
it behaved uh for us uh in the the Key
Bank partner Channel as well as outside
of that uh in terms of the total payout
I understand there was you know uh you
know categorization or reclassification
ation but just in terms of payout has
there been a demand for increase in
payouts for us and uh have you seen any
kind of anomalies in the industry
otherwise so uh overall if you see for
us as a company expense of management
has stayed within the range uh and it's
actually it's come down uh from a 27.3
to 26.9 uh so Frankly Speaking uh there
is no Accel increase but but in certain
Pockets where we have seen a bit of an
acceleration you will see that
dynamically we will go again to what our
basic thesis has been uh we will change
that we can get uh viable business uh in
terms of acquiring it uh in a way to
some extent you can see our motor market
share also is reflecting that we had a
calibrated growth uh to probably
maintain profitability over just market
share growth so you can read in terms of
what's Happening overarchingly uh but
overall we seem to be in control uh at
this point of
time okay thank you so much all yeah
than
thanks thank you our next question is
from the line of PES Jen from Mo lawal
please go
ahead Mr PR Jen your line has been
unmuted you can
go hi congratulations great set of
numbers uh firstly uh you know uh I just
missed the agency count number can you
just repeat
the it's about 1 lak 122,000 which
includes the agency that includes the
point of sale distribution as well so
this was it is 1 lak 122,000 this number
at the end of uh uh ear period was about
13,000 okay okay and just on the you
know previous question uh sorry to
interrupt Mr Jen we request you to use
your handset please as your audio is M
sir thank you is this
better hello hello your voice is
slightly more feeble uh PR we can't hear
you
clearly I'll come back in the KE sorry
thank you
sir our next question is from the line
of mukar L from noama wealth management
please go
ahead I uh good evening and
congratulations on a good set of numbers
couple of questions
uh one we seeing a good increase in the
crop business uh that you're doing this
year what is the
philosophy uh behind that uh I remember
in the past you wanted to avoid that
business and uh I I also know that you
got this business again from
bti uh so is that only those States or
are you also growing some of the other
states uh so that's that's one second uh
again I'm just going back to a guidance
of
102% given that your performance is
quite strong and you know in first half
itself you are at
102.7 so uh are you being a little bit
too
conservative over
here um and finally um you know most of
the industry is uh ahead or sorry is not
meeting the uh eom uh norms right now um
you know so what regulatory action can
we expect and and what would you say uh
by when uh will the regulator start
looking at this and implementing
this thanks let me answer it in the same
sequence one on crop there is no change
in philosophy as gopal had explained
that I think SJ explained that there are
certain months where you book a premium
it just shows up in that quarter uh in
aggregate our share of crop business
which we have guided the market was to
be would be around 5% of total business
uh for the annual uh business not on a
quarterly basis and I think we'll stay
at at that kind of range we are not
significantly growing our crop book uh
in spite of the fact that we believe
some players in the market are trying to
do that because of the advantage that
they get on E but philosophically we
don't believe that's the right strategy
right approach so we are not doing that
uh uh there was some amount of booking
in the kar season because most of the
business for us is in the karif market
Kar period so it's it's a bit higher in
this quarter that's about all secondly
most of the propop that we' got is in
the 18810 model uh so it's a reasonably
well contained uh business and our
experience in the last couple of years
has been very reasonably positive on the
approach that you
had in terms of your question on uh uh
the combined isue coming to question on
combin to add you know whether we are
being conservative that's your call you
you take your own views about whether we
being combined as conservative I think
as I said the guidance should remain the
same if you can outperform all of you
should be happy uh third in terms of the
regulatory action uh look it's not for
us to talk about what the regulator will
do uh but uh at least we uh hope and we
think that this time the regulator is
very serious about this uh at the same
time this is not about a quarterly
number that they're monitoring they will
monit they given a leway for a company
on an annual basis and my my my sense is
that the end of the year they look at
who is improved and who's not improved
and who's gone beyond uh
30% uh so I think it would be wise for
most companies which are already running
at higher than that number I think it
would be wise for them to bring it under
control but as I said it's not for us to
talk about what the regulator will do
that's a question that uh in a sense
your time will give us the answer and
you'll see what the regulator does
thanks just a follow up on this sir are
we seeing a heightened comparative
intensity in the group health uh segment
also uh to sort of meet the E Norms I
think gopal answered that and you know
in the first quarter we saw the market
on Group Health to be better and we we
had a much higher shares uh this quarter
we've seen some amount of uh aggression
and in fact we've seen some otherwise
sensible companies by very large chunky
groupal businesses our senses it's
probably to manage the extens of
management but at the end of the day
business is not just about expensive
management business is about combined
right so you have to do it in a manner
which is sensible so uh We'll Be
watchful uh and we'll see what what
happens but overall at this point in
time we are quite comfortable with the
group health business that we
writing got it uh thank you and all the
best thank you our next question is from
the line of nishin chawat from kotak
institutional equities please go ahead
uh thanks for taking my question uh just
a small one uh you know when I look at
the monthly uh you know monthly figures
for motor TP business I was just curious
that uh you know did you do any
transaction in the last month uh you
know just as something that you had done
probably in the Feb or March month last
year no n they've not done any
transaction perfect thanks that answers
my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of supratim data from Ambit Capital
please go
ahead thanks for the
opportunity uh just wanted to understand
a few things so one the 0.48 billion of
you know ncat losses which lines of
business are those attribut
to think it's been largely so this quar
uh has been largely let's say relatively
retailed uh so we have had a higher
proportion of losses coming in from the
motor line of business but equally we
have also had some amount of claims
coming in on the property side unlike
water one where relatively the uh lots
of roughly about 35 crores which was the
cat losses in q1 that was largely
property heavy as compared to
motor got it and uh within so if I
adjust for that nasat losses then in the
motor OD line then that would result in
the loss ratio being lower than 60% is
that a correct assumption and then my
followup question to that is you know
how sustainable is this loss ratio going
forward
uh so uh I had kind of already responded
to that but just to kind of rate rate uh
again and we will keep saying this and
you will get to hear us from time and
again you should never look at quarterly
numbers uh and largely it is better to
kind of look at numbers more on a yearly
basis U just to kind of rate rate on
motor own damage I think the loss ratio
depending on the kind of mix of business
that we write in motor we are
comfortable at a loss ratio range
between 65 to 70%
uh that's the range depending on what
kind of mix of business we write and on
TP again it's better to kind of look at
more annual numbers uh which is largely
reflective of the loss ratio range that
one would be comfortable writing so
hence to that extent whether you adjust
it for the quarter to losses from cat in
the loss ratios but if you do that on a
simple basis then obviously yes the loss
ratio will definitely look better than
what the reported numbers are but having
said that I think the range at which we
are comfortable at is between 65 to uh
70% and what equally we need to remember
is that whatever be the amount of losses
I think we do have uh appropriate
reinsurance support such that uh if
there's a very large uh Cat event having
an impact on the net that gets
appropriately protected through
necessary reinsurance
management got it and just one last
question so on the fire side there has
been a Slowdown in the second quarter so
just wanted to understand how much of
this is due to the IID burn rates being
removed uh versus you know overall
competition or you know you wanting to
not write some kind of business so just
wanted to understand so on that the
experience as what we discussed at the
end of in the first quarter is the same
which is that roughly about 5 6%
reduction from the earlier rates which
is uh better than what we had actually
we had anticipated the beginning of the
year we have to if this holds in terms
of fire there are you know maybe one or
two large policies that have got moved
from period to you know you know and
there's some uh you know policies have
earlier booked in this period which may
have got moved somewhere else so you
should look at the numbers with a longer
period rather than just a quarter the
only thing just to add to that I think
having said that I think if you look at
across segments on the commercial lines
I think we still continue to outperform
the market I think we continue to upate
Market market share uh in fire as a line
of business or whether you take any of
the other commercial lines we continue
to outgrow the
market uh thank you that's very helpful
thank you thank you ladies and gentlemen
due to time constraint that was the last
question of our question and answer
session I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr bav Das Gupta for
closing
comment uh thank you thank you everyone
uh I think all of you have been great
support to uh to the and me personally
and I really want to take this
opportunity to thank all of you for
being a great analyst and and investors
in our company uh as I said earlier uh
I'm hoping that you'll continue to
engage with us as you have in the past
and Sanji wants to have the last
word no I think absolute pleasure and uh
really Keen to interact with each one of
you personally as in when uh your
schedule permits uh nothing much to add
but absolutely in agreement with bav
that uh we've had you know great inputs
and discussions with all of you and that
continues thank you so much and let's
meet up soon thank
you thank you thank you on behalf of ICI
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your
lines